Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
My name is Katrin and today we have a very dangerous lesson for you guys.
我叫Katrin，今天我们要给大家上一节非常危险的课。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about guns or specifically about weapons.
今天我们要讨论枪支，更具体地说是武器。
So yeah, we're talking about kinds of guns.
是的，我们正在讨论各种枪支。
There are more than I think I ever knew and we're going to discuss about six today.
比我以为的还要多，我们今天要讨论其中六个。
But before we get going, Marco, we've got a phrase in vocabulary preview.
不过在我们开始之前，Marco，我们有一个短语要预习一下。
That's right.
没错。
So today on vocabulary preview, we're going to take a look at shooting range.
今天在词汇预览环节，我们要来看看“射击场”这个词。
Have you ever been to one of these places?
你去过这种地方吗？
Yes, a shooting range.
是的，一个射击场。
It's a place like you say, and it's a place where you can fire your weapons or you can
就像你说的那样，那是一个地方，你可以开枪射击，或者
use guns safely so you don't kill anyone or you don't hurt someone.
安全使用枪支，这样你就不会杀死任何人或伤害到别人。
No, basically, yeah, it's a place to practice shooting.
不，基本上，是的，那是个练习射击的地方。
So maybe for example, if you want to practice how to shoot guns, you go to this place and
所以比如说，如果你想练习射击，就可以去这个地方。
they have special things to help you improve your shooting abilities.
他们有专门的设备来帮助你提高投篮能力。
Usually these are very, very secure.
通常这些都非常非常安全。
They have guards and things because you don't want to give the guns out to anybody.
他们有警卫之类的，因为枪不能随便发给任何人。
That's right.
没错。
But let's listen to today's dialogue about a shooting range and find out what kinds of
不过，我们先听听今天关于射击场的对话，看看他们有哪些
guns they have.
枪械。
Hey Nick, what are you up to?
嘿，尼克，你在忙什么？
Not much.
没什么。
Just heading over to the shooting range.
正要去射击场。
You want to come?
你想一起来吗？
Seriously?
真的吗？
You mean to fire a real weapon?
你是说去开真枪？
I don't know, man.
我不知道，老兄。
Yeah, it will be fun.
当然，会很好玩的。
I have a 9mm pistol that's really easy to shoot.
我有一把9毫米手枪，很容易上手。
I also have a revolver that's really fun too.
我还有一把左轮手枪，也很有意思。
They have big targets at the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim.
射击场有大靶子，我们可以用来练习，提高你的瞄准。
Yeah, that would be cool.
嗯，那挺酷的。
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun.
也许我还能试试其他武器，比如机枪或霰弹枪。
Maybe even a rocket launcher or an anti-tank missile.
甚至火箭筒或反坦克导弹。
Or what about a flamethrower?
或者喷火器怎么样？
Whoa, take it easy there, Rambo.
哇，悠着点，兰博。
Don't get carried away.
别太激动了。
These weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them properly.
这些武器不是玩具，你得先学会怎么正确操作它们。
There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe.
为了安全，你必须遵守一些基本规则。
For example, never handle a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself.
例如，绝不要碰你自己没有检查过的武器。
Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber and never put your finger to the trigger
始终确保枪膛里没有东西，并且永远不要把手指放在扳机上，
unless you are ready to shoot.
除非你准备开枪。
Wow, I didn't know.
哇，我以前不知道。
It always looks so cool and easy in the movies.
电影里看起来总是那么酷又简单。
The reality is different, you know.
现实可不一样，你知道的。
Running and firing a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies.
边跑边开枪比电影里难多了。
So are you ready?
那你准备好了吗？
Let's do it!
来吧！
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously this guy was very excited about using these weapons.
显然这家伙对使用这些武器非常兴奋。
And you may have heard that we're using this word weapons.
你可能听到我们用了“武器”这个词。
It's basically all of these things.
它基本上涵盖了所有这些物品。
I guess anything that can be used in defense or hurt someone.
我想任何可以用来防御或伤害别人的东西都算。
Yes, anything that can be used to hurt someone as a weapon.
是的，任何可以用来伤害别人的东西都是武器。
So a knife can be a weapon, not just guns.
所以刀也可以是武器，不只是枪。
Guns are a kind of weapon.
枪是一种武器。
That's right.
没错。
So if we're looking at our first type of gun or our first type of weapon, we have a 9mm
那么，如果我们看第一种枪或第一种武器，我们有9毫米口径的。
pistol.
手枪。
Okay, so the weapon is the pistol.
好的，所以武器就是手枪。
And the pistol is basically a handgun.
而手枪基本上就是一种手槍。
But it comes in different sizes.
但它有不同的尺寸。
So that's what the 9mm refers to.
所以这就是9毫米所指的意思。
That's right.
没错。
That's the size of the projectile that will come out of the weapon.
那是从武器中射出的弹丸的尺寸。
And a pistol, as you said, it's a handgun.
而手枪，就像你说的，是一种手槍。
It's usually small.
它通常很小。
And it can fit in your hand, so you can use just one hand to use this weapon.
它可以握在手里，所以你只用一只手就能使用这种武器。
Okay, so there's a similar handgun that's a little bit bigger.
好的，还有一种类似的手槍，稍微大一点。
That's called a revolver.
那叫左轮手枪。
That's right, a revolver.
没错，左轮手枪。
So this one has a revolving chamber.
所以这种枪有一个旋转弹膛。
So you kind of see this in the old western movies when they have six bullets, right?
你在老西部片里经常看到，它们有六发子弹，对吧？
And they like swing their guns into their side holsters.
他们喜欢把枪甩进腰间的枪套里。
Yeah.
嗯。
Well, yeah, that's right.
嗯，是的，没错。
The revolver refers to the...
左轮手枪指的是...
Well, to revolve, it means to move around, to spin.
嗯，“revolve”意思是旋转、转动。
That's right.
没错。
So the place with the bullets basically spins after you shoot the gun.
所以装子弹的那个地方基本上在你开枪后会旋转。
That's right.
没错。
So that's why it's called a revolver.
所以这就是为什么它叫左轮手枪。
Unlike the pistol, the pistol will usually not really have a revolver.
不像手枪，手枪通常没有转轮。
It will have a magazine.
它会有弹匣。
Okay.
好的。
Now, moving on to our next type of weapon, we have the very famous machine gun.
现在，我们来看下一种武器，非常著名的机枪。
That's the one that shoots off really fast.
就是那种射速很快的枪。
And so basically, it's called a machine gun because it's automatically releasing all these
基本上，它叫机枪是因为它会自动连续发射
bullets at once.
子弹。
You just pull the trigger and many, many, many bullets come out.
你只要扣动扳机，就会射出很多很多子弹。
That's right.
没错。
So in a pistol or in a revolver, usually you have to press the trigger once and it shoots
所以用手枪或左轮手枪时，通常你扣一次扳机
only once.
只射一发。
But in a machine gun, you can keep it pressed and all these bullets will start flying out.
但用机枪时，你可以一直扣着扳机，子弹就会开始飞出来。
Very, very dangerous.
非常非常危险。
Very dangerous.
非常危险。
Okay.
好的。
So now moving on to the next one, we also took a look at a shotgun.
那么现在来看下一种，我们还看了霰弹枪。
Okay.
好的。
This is...
这个……
Well, this is not the biggest gun we're going to talk about today.
嗯，这不是我们今天要讲的最大的枪。
But it's a very large gun, very long, and you have to use two hands to hold it.
但它是一种很大的枪，很长，你得用两只手才能握住。
This is what you usually use when you go hunting, right?
这通常是你去打猎时用的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, it's very long and it's very loud.
就像你说的，它很长，声音也很大。
And it doesn't really shoot bullets.
而且它射的不是子弹。
It shoots little pellets, little cartridges that are filled with little rocks, for example.
它射的是小弹丸、小弹壳，里面装满了小石子之类的东西。
And that's what it shoots.
这就是它射的东西。
And this is why it's not very precise like a machine gun or a handgun, but it does a
这就是为什么它不像机枪或手枪那么精准，但
lot of damage.
破坏力很大。
Absolutely.
绝对。
And what's something else that does a lot of damage?
还有什么东西破坏力很大？
Our next gun will do that.
我们下一种枪就能做到。
Well, this guy got a little bit excited and he said he wanted to use a rocket launcher.
嗯，这家伙有点兴奋了，他说他想用火箭筒。
Okay.
好的。
So you know what a rocket is.
所以你知道火箭是什么。
A rocket is something that's basically a projectile that goes into the sky and can basically blow
火箭基本上是一种射向天空的抛射物，可以
up big buildings or cars.
炸毁大楼或汽车。
That's right.
没错。
And that's what a rocket launcher is.
这就是火箭筒。
Now, maybe you've heard of the word bazooka.
现在，你可能听说过“巴祖卡”这个词。
A bazooka is a type of rocket launcher.
巴祖卡是一种火箭筒。
It's the one...
就是那种……
It's very, very, very wide and it's circular.
它非常非常宽，而且是圆形的。
And you usually see it in movies like Rambo, we talked about, where Rambo will hold it
你通常在电影里看到它，比如我们聊过的《第一滴血》，兰博会把它扛在
on one shoulder.
一个肩膀上。
It's so big.
它太大了。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
And the rocket shoots out and can destroy huge buildings.
然后火箭射出去，可以摧毁巨大的建筑。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
So that's why it's called a rocket launcher.
所以这就是为什么它叫火箭筒。
Now for our last type of weapon, we have a flamethrower.
现在，我们最后一种武器是火焰喷射器。
Okay.
好的。
Well, a flame refers to fire.
嗯，火焰指的是火。
So fire has flames.
所以火有火焰。
Those are the parts that kind of come up on a fire.
就是火苗往上窜的那些部分。
They're red and orange.
它们是红色和橙色的。
And a flamethrower is a device, is a weapon that will shoot flames, not bullets.
火焰喷射器是一种装置，一种武器，它会喷出火焰，而不是子弹。
Exactly.
没错。
It was very popular back in World War II to actually shoot the flamethrower into bunkers
它在二战时期非常流行，用来向碉堡
or into holes because then this is how you can get people out of there.
或洞穴里喷射火焰，因为这样可以把人逼出来。
And I think flamethrowers are used now to some sort of degree like to fumigate sometimes
我觉得火焰喷射器现在某种程度上还在用，比如有时用来熏蒸
or to burn weeds when you're in a field.
或在田里烧杂草。
Right.
对。
But they're not really used as weapons anymore.
但它们现在不太作为武器使用了。
Although I think that I've seen a number of them in action movies.
虽然我觉得我在动作片里见过不少。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
In action movies, of course.
在动作片里，当然。
So we have a lot of guns, a lot of different types of weapons.
所以我们有很多枪，很多不同类型的武器。
Why don't we go back to the dialogue?
我们不如回到对话吧？
Let's listen to it again and we'll be back soon with Fluency Builder.
我们再听一遍，然后很快回来做流利度练习。
Hey Nick.
嘿，尼克。
What are you up to?
你在干嘛？
Not much.
没什么。
Just heading over to the shooting range.
正要去射击场。
You want to come?
你想来吗？
Seriously?
真的吗？
You mean to fire a real weapon?
你是说开真枪？
I don't know, man.
我不知道，老兄。
Yeah, it will be fun.
是啊，会很好玩的。
I have a 9mm pistol that's really easy to shoot.
我有一把9毫米手枪，很容易打。
I also have a revolver that's really fun too.
我还有一把左轮手枪，也挺好玩的。
They have big targets at the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim.
射击场有大靶子，我们可以用来练习，提高你的瞄准。
Yeah, that would be cool.
是啊，那会很酷。
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun.
也许我还能试试其他武器，比如机枪或霰弹枪。
Maybe even a rocket launcher or an anti-tank missile.
甚至火箭筒或反坦克导弹也行。
Or what about a flamethrower?
或者火焰喷射器怎么样？
Whoa, take it easy there, Rambo.
哇，悠着点，兰博。
Don't get carried away.
别太得意忘形了。
These weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them properly.
这些武器不是玩具，你得先学会怎么正确操作。
There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe.
为了安全，有一些基本规则你必须遵守。
For example, never handle a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself.
比如，永远不要碰你没亲自检查过的武器。
Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber and never put your finger to the trigger
一定要确保枪膛里没有东西，而且永远不要把手指放在扳机上，
unless you are ready to shoot.
除非你准备开枪。
Wow, I didn't know.
哇，我不知道这些。
It always looks so cool and easy in the movies.
电影里看起来总是又酷又简单。
The reality is different, you know.
现实可不一样，你知道吗。
Running and firing a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies.
边跑边开枪比电影里难多了。
So are you ready?
那你准备好了吗？
Let's do it.
开始吧。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at our phrases that we've picked out for you on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看在Fluency Builder上为你们挑选的短语。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
So this first phrase comes from the beginning of today's dialogue when Nick is saying,
第一个短语来自今天对话的开头，尼克说：
well I'm not doing much, I'm just heading over to the shooting range.
“嗯，我没做什么，只是要去射击场。”
That's right.
没错。
So we know what shooting range is but when he says I'm heading over to the shooting range.
我们知道射击场是什么，但他说“我要去射击场”时。
Well this can be confusing because to head over has nothing to do with the head on your
这可能会让人困惑，因为“head over”和你身体上的头无关。
body.
无关。
Right.
对。
It means I'm going towards some place.
它的意思是“我正前往某个地方”。
I'm going to this place.
我要去这个地方。
So it's just another way of saying going to, right?
所以这只是“going to”的另一种说法，对吧？
So for example, you can say I'm heading over to my friend's house this afternoon.
比如，你可以说“我今天下午要去朋友家”。
That's right, so I'm going to my friend's house this afternoon.
没错，就是“我今天下午要去朋友家”。
But remember that this is a pretty relaxed, pretty informal way of saying something so
但记住，这是一种很随意、非正式的说法。
you wouldn't say I'm heading over to work.
所以你不会说“我要去上班”。
Right.
没错。
You say hey I'm heading over to his house to hang out or I'm heading over to the pizza
你说“嘿，我要去他家玩”或者“我要去披萨店”
restaurant to grab a bite to eat.
吃点东西。
That's right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So now obviously we saw that one of the guys got very excited about the idea of using all
所以现在我们看到其中一个人对使用所有这些酷炫武器的想法非常兴奋，
these cool weapons and his friend said whoa, take it easy there Rambo.
他的朋友说：“哇，悠着点，兰博。”
Don't get carried away.
别太激动了。
I love this phrase.
我喜欢这个短语。
This phrase is something you say to someone who is maybe too excited about something.
这个短语是用来对可能对某事过于兴奋的人说的。
That's right.
对。
It means don't go crazy.
它的意思是别发疯。
Don't exaggerate.
别夸张。
Right.
没错。
So maybe at the shooting range they'll have a revolver and they'll have a pistol but they're
所以在射击场，他们可能会有左轮手枪和手枪，但
probably not going to have a rocket launcher or as he said an anti-tank missile.
可能不会有火箭筒或者像他说的反坦克导弹。
These are crazy weapons from movies.
这些都是电影里的疯狂武器。
And so the friend is saying no, you're exaggerating.
所以朋友在说：“不，你夸张了。”
Don't get carried away.
别太激动了。
Now for example maybe you go to the mall and you go shopping and maybe you got a little
比如你去商场购物，可能有点
bit carried away and you spent too much money.
一时冲动，结果花太多钱了。
That always happens to me during the holidays.
假期里我经常这样。
I get carried away and I buy way too much stuff.
我一时冲动，买了一大堆东西。
That's right.
没错。
So that's the way that you would use carried away.
这就是“carried away”的用法。
And now for our last phrase, he was actually explaining a couple of rules of weapon handling
现在来看最后一个短语，他当时在解释几条武器操作规则，
and he said that there are some rules that he has to abide by.
他说有些规则他必须遵守。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a fixed phrase.
这是一个固定短语。
We use the verb to abide with a word like the rules.
我们用动词“abide”搭配像“rules”这样的词。
So to abide by the rules or we must all abide by the rules.
所以是“abide by the rules”，或者“我们必须遵守规则”。
This is a fancy way of saying to follow the rules or to recognize the rules.
这是一种比较正式的说法，意思是“遵守规则”或“承认规则”。
That's right.
没错。
So you have to abide by the rules of your school or maybe you have to, everyone has
所以你必须遵守学校的规则，或者也许你必须——每个人都必须遵守法律。
to abide by the law.
每个人都必须遵守法律。
Right.
对。
Or some people can say there are rules in the Bible that other people abide by.
或者有些人会说，圣经里有其他人遵守的规则。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great stuff.
内容很丰富。
I think we've taken a look at a lot of different types of weapons and phrases.
我想我们已经看了很多不同类型的武器和短语。
So pretty interesting stuff.
所以挺有意思的。
Why don't we listen to it for the last time.
我们最后再听一遍吧。
Hey Nick.
嘿，尼克。
What are you up to?
你在忙什么？
Not much.
没什么。
Just heading over to the shooting range.
正要去射击场。
You want to come?
你想来吗？
Seriously?
真的吗？
You mean to fire a real weapon?
你是说去开真枪？
I don't know man.
我不知道，老兄。
Yeah.
是啊。
I'm having fun.
我玩得很开心。
I have a 9mm pistol that's really easy to shoot.
我有一把9毫米手枪，很容易打。
I also have a revolver that's really fun too.
我还有一把左轮手枪，也很好玩。
They have big targets at the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim.
射击场有大靶子，我们可以用来练习，提高你的瞄准。
Yeah.
是啊。
That would be cool.
那会很酷。
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun.
也许我还能试试其他武器，比如机枪或霰弹枪。
Maybe even a rocket launcher or an anti-tank missile.
甚至火箭筒或反坦克导弹。
Or what about a flamethrower?
或者火焰喷射器怎么样？
Whoa.
哇。
Take it easy there Rambo.
悠着点，兰博。
Don't get carried away.
别得意忘形。
These weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them properly.
这些武器不是玩具，你必须先学会如何正确操作。
There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe.
为了安全，你必须遵守一些基本规则。
For example, never handle a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself.
比如，永远不要碰你没检查过的武器。
Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber and never put your finger to the trigger
始终确保枪膛里没有东西，并且永远不要把手指放在扳机上，
unless you are ready to shoot.
除非你准备好射击。
Wow.
哇。
I didn't know.
我不知道。
It always looks so cool and easy in the movies.
在电影里看起来总是那么酷又简单。
The reality is different you know.
现实可不一样，你知道的。
Running and firing a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies.
边跑边开枪比电影里难多了。
So are you ready?
那你准备好了吗？
Let's do it.
来吧。
All right we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about weapons and pistols and all this.
所以说到武器、手枪这些。
Have you ever used one of these?
你用过这些吗？
Have you ever shot?
你开过枪吗？
I have.
我开过。
I have been to a couple shooting ranges and have fired a couple of guns.
我去过几个射击场，开过几把枪。
I've never fired a shotgun.
我从没开过霰弹枪。
They don't usually.
他们通常不提供。
Well sometimes.
嗯，有时候有。
Yeah.
是啊。
Sometimes they have a shotgun.
有时候他们有霰弹枪。
Sometimes they have them.
有时候他们会有。
Sure.
当然。
But I've shot pistols before.
但我以前开过手枪。
And do you like it?
你喜欢吗？
I like it.
我喜欢。
It's an interesting activity.
这是一项有趣的活动。
I don't know how I feel about using guns on people but I understand why hunting is an
我不知道怎么看待对人用枪，但我理解为什么打猎是
enjoyable sport because there is a sport aspect to it.
一项令人愉快的运动，因为它有运动的一面。
You know you really have to control your body and you can improve.
你知道，你真的需要控制你的身体，而且你可以进步。
You can get better.
你可以变得更好。
It's like darts but with loud guns.
就像飞镖，但枪声很响。
And it's very hard to aim actually to hit something.
而且实际上瞄准击中目标非常难。
People think it's very easy like in the movies.
人们以为像电影里那样很容易。
Well and I think it's particularly hard with handguns.
嗯，我觉得用手枪尤其难。
Yes.
是的。
Because they're very powerful.
因为它们威力很大。
Some of them can be very powerful.
有些可能威力非常大。
And so there's a kick.
所以会有后坐力。
Yeah.
是啊。
And you don't realize it the first time you shoot a gun.
你第一次开枪时不会意识到这一点。
You're like oh that was way harder than it looks in the movies.
你会想，哦，这比电影里看起来难多了。
I bet you're a good shot right?
我猜你枪法很好，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
I've always really enjoyed weapons and my aim is alright.
我一直很喜欢武器，我的瞄准还行。
Although my eyesight kind of.
虽然我的视力有点……
I need to use glasses so it can be a little bit tricky sometimes.
我需要戴眼镜，所以有时候会有点麻烦。
Especially when you shoot a weapon sometimes it's very.
尤其是开枪的时候，有时会非常……
You just cleaned it so it has a lot of oil and it'll kick out into your face and get
你刚擦干净，上面有很多油，它会溅到你脸上，
your glasses wet.
弄湿你的眼镜。
Well that's why we use goggles at the shooting ranges that I go to.
嗯，这就是为什么我去射击场时戴护目镜。
But I'm curious to know have you guys ever shot a gun before?
但我很好奇，你们以前开过枪吗？
Have you ever been to a shooting range?
你们去过射击场吗？
Are shooting ranges legal in your country?
你们国家射击场合法吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Some places they're not.
有些地方不合法。
Yeah.
嗯。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
Alright.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们那儿见。
My name's Andrew Cline for Android Authenticated and we'll see ya!
我是 Android Authenticated 的 Andrew Cline，再见！